Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 32.
We are asked to find the maximum and the minimum in an array of integers, so was the video and think
about it.
Please write your solution in the comments below.
In order to discuss your points and think about it, OK, so let's begin.
We will consider.
We have the first step and into array called my array equal to.
Twelve.
OK.
And I will create two variables of type and max equal to my array at Index zero.
I will demonstrate it later on why we are doing this and my array and thanks.
We consider that the minimum is at the first element and the maximum is the first.
And we start making that comparison.
So this is the second step and the first step here.
I like creating valuables.
And here.
The second step would be that comparisons there,
so we start using the for each loop, looping through all the elements to find the minimum.
So and a equals to my brain.
So for every element in my array.
We are creating an integer a such that this a I would use it in finding the minimum and the maximum
f a less than minimum than minimum equal to a cake.
This is very simple.
If minimum?
Is less than there any element inside this loop and inside this array make this element, the new element
would be them M..
OK.
If a is greater than maximum it if if any element in this array is greater than the maximum, which
is the first element, then.
Make it as the enemy, OK, it's very simple, OK?
Outside the loop system that out duct Brent and the maximum here is Max and the management system that
out the brand.
Print and.
The minimum.
Men.
OK.
It's very simple.
Now, let's test and see.
And later, I will show you what we have done.
OK, let's scroll up.
And here we go.
We have the maximum two for one and the minimum is 12.
So what we have done?
I will go up here.
So consider we have an array here.
It is the first element, 12, four, four.
Oops!
For four.
Eight five.
Two for one.
Five to.
And 14.
OK.
We consider in case of minimum, we.
Or maximum, let me consider first at the maximum maximum, my rate equal to zero at index zero.
This is index zero one, two three and four five.
OK.
So we consider the minimum suggest that the maximum is at the index zero.
We start comparing if.
A greater than the maximum, then make maximum equal to a we start 12 less greater than 40 for no.
So make 44 at index zero.
So the new loop, the new array, you can consider it as this.
40 now, 44.
This is here.
44 is less than or certainly greater than 85.
Yes.
So.
That 85 is greater than 44, so the first element would be eighty five.
OK.
Eighty five.
Here it is eight, eight, five two four, one five two and one four again, eight five, comparing
it with two four one.
Yes, two four one is greater than eight five two two four one four four eight five two four one five
two one four zero one four.
OK, now continue the comparison two four one is great is greater than five.
Two.
Yes to four.
So keep it at the index zero two four one is greater than 14.
Yes, so keep it at index zero.
And here we have reached the end of that array.
So go and and return two for one as the maximum.
In the same way it's applicable for finding that minimum, it's we.
We consider the first element is the minimum and we start comparing it.
If we find any element that is less than the minimum at index zero.
Then go and replace the minimum with and that value.
Then you value that it's let.